intetics.com 2019-11-13

# Privacy Policy | Intetics

## Introduction

Thank you for visiting our website and showing interest in our Company. Your privacy is precious to us. In this Privacy Policy we will explain how we collect data about you, how we use it and how it is protected. Depending on your online activity, different types of data may be collected for different purposes and shared with different parties in various countries. Please find the activity which is relevant to you below.

## Terminology

A **Cookie** is a small file with a string of letters and numbers which is created on your device when you are browsing websites. Cookies serve as unique identifiers to distinguish your visits from the visits of other users. Cookies can also be used to store your personal preferences on websites or to save your login data.

The **General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) is a regulation which was issued by authorized bodies of the European Union to greatly improve the protection of personal data for all individuals within the EU.

 **Legitimate** interest means that we can process your personal data if we have a genuine and legal reason to do so and that we are not harming your rights and interests. In our case, it means that when our website gathers information about your visit, we use this data for our legitimate business interests to provide you with outstanding software products and services. Before doing this, though, we also carefully consider and balance any potential impact that it may have on you and your rights.

 **Personal data** means any information that identifies you or helps in the determination of your potential identification along with any information that relates to you in that case.

 **Tag** is a piece of code on a website that sends information to a third party, such as Google Analytics.

## Activities

### Browsing the website

Here at Intetics we are devoted to providing you with only the best of what there is to offer. That is why we continually strive to make our website as simple and informative as possible. Another part of the job is determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising, thus improving our products, services, systems and relationships with you. For these purposes we collect usage statistics which are further analyzed and used to monitor your interactions with our advertisements and web pages. We also place social media buttons on some pages to let you share the content which you liked with your friends.

The processing of your personal data is based on one of the lawful grounds called "Legitimate interest". You can find out what it refers to in the Terminology section of this privacy policy.

Just as many other websites in the world do, we use cookies (see the Terminology). When you open our website, cookies are created on your device. When your open it the next time, cookies are sent back to us, thus letting us know you’ve already been there. We don’t create cookies ourselves, but we use 3rd party providers who do it for us. Below you can find a list with the links to their privacy policies explaining the purposes for which they process your data, how long they keep it (retention periods) etc.

 **Google Analytics** component is embedded into all pages of the website. With the help of cookies it collects and analyzes visitors' behavior: from which sites they come (for example, from Google search results), from which IP and country, which pages they open, when it happened, how long they stayed on the pages, which browser was used, and which operating system and language. This data is highly anonymous and is used to optimize the content of our website. The retention period for this data is set to 26 months. You can install the Google Analytics opt-out in your browser to prohibit Google Analytics JavaScript from sending information to Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

You can find the Google Analytics Privacy Policy [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Google Analytics belongs to Google Inc. which is situated outside the EU and EEA, namely in the USA. Its address is Google, Google Data Protection Office, 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, California 94043, USA. Hense, your data is transferred there on the bases of the EU-US Privacy Shield adequacy decision ("Privacy Shield").

We use **Google Tag Manager** which makes managing tags (see the Terminology) much easier. Google Tag Manager neither collects personal data nor accesses the data which is collected by tags that we manage with it. More information about Google tag manager can be found [here](https://www.google.com/analytics/tag-manager/use-policy/).

 **Google AdWords** is a service which shows advertisements in Google search results and on 3rd party websites included into the Google Display Network. If you reach our website through a link provided by Google AdWords, a cookie is placed on your device. Then Google converts these cookies into anonymous statistics which we use to analyze the efficiency of our advertisements.

You can find privacy information about AdWords [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads). Google Adwords belongs to Google Inc. which is situated outside the EU and EEA, namely in the USA. Its address is Google, Google Data Protection Office, 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, California 94043, USA. Hense, your data is transferred there on the bases of the EU-US Privacy Shield adequacy decision ("Privacy Shield").

 **AddThis** component enables buttons for sharing our publications in Xing, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+. When you go through the pages where this button is displayed, information about your visit (mainly the same as in the case of Google Analytics) is uploaded to AddThis, which enables them to show you personalized advertisements.

We cannot identify you personally using the above statistics because we can only see the aggregated and anonymized data. If you don’t want your behavior to be tracked, you may wish to disable cookies in your browser. Please follow the links to further educate yourself on how to manage cookies: [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en), [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences), [Edge](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy), [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-my/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies), [Safari](https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac).

You can find AddThis Privacy Policy [here](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy). This service belongs to Oracle Corporation located in the US (Chief Privacy Officer Oracle Corporation, 10 Van De Graaff Dr., Burlington, MA 01803, United States of America). Oracle corporation and its subsidiaries and affiliates comply with the EU-US Privacy Shield adequacy decision ("Privacy Shield").

Articles with buttons for sharing them in **Xing** , **Facebook** , **Twitter** , **LinkedIn** and **Google+** have embedded code which displays the buttons and informs these social networks about your visits. If at the time of your browsing you were logged into these social networks, they can recognize you personally and add this information to your profile. Later this data may be used for showing you targeted advertisements.

XING social network service is provided by XING AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. XING's privacy policy can be found [here](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy). Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA. Facebook's privacy policy can be found [here](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php). Twitter social networking web-service belongs to Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Twitter's privacy policy can be found [here](https://twitter.com/en/privacy). LinkedIn social network is operated by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Linkedin's privacy policy can be found [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy). Facebook, Twitter and Linkedin are located in the USA. Your data is transferred there on the bases of the EU-US Privacy Shield adequacy decision ("Privacy Shield").

If you prefer not to link your activity with your profiles in social networks, you may wish to log out of them before using our website. Nevertheless, we neither collect nor obtain this information from social network providers.

With regard to the information described in this section you have the following rights:

  * the right of access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure ('right to be forgotten');
  * the right to restriction of processing;
  * the right to object; and
  * the right to lodge a complaint.

You can read what each of these rights means in the section Your rights of this Privacy Policy. Please also read Logs of the web server.

### Requesting our white papers or demos

When you download white papers we ask for your name, business email, phone number and company address to receive your feedback and improve our publications, to research which factors have the most influence in spurring interest in our articles and our company, and to inform you about our new products and services. We have legitimate interest to process received data for direct B2B marketing purposes, because by downloading whitepapers you show your interest in our products and knowledge, and we have the interest to increase our sales.

To provide you with the demos you requested, we need to customize them for the sphere in which your business operates. For this purpose, we ask you about your company. After customizing the demo, we will send it to your email with instructions on how to use it. We will also ask for your feedback to provide you with better services and products.

Your contact information will be removed from our database after 36 months from the time you submitted it, or since your last reply.

We do not share this data with 3rd parties.

With regard to the information described in this section you have the following rights:

  * the right of access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure ('right to be forgotten');
  * the right to restriction of processing;
  * the right to object; and
  * the right to lodge a complaint.

You can read what each of these rights means in the section Your rights of this Privacy Policy. Please also read Browsing the website, Using contact forms and Logs of the web server.

### Applying for a job

If you apply for a job we obviously process your contact details, CV, professional qualifications, salary expectations, references and information in social media that you made publicly accessible.

Usually we get this information from you but we may also contact your previous employers, colleagues and referees when it is necessary to complete, and clarify or confirm the information about you.

We process this data based on the legal basis which is called “legitimate interest” (see the Terminology section). We do it to assess your experience and qualifications, and to make sure that the position we offer suits you the best. This data helps us fill the vacancies with the best suited candidates and provides you with a fair and objective employment process as well.

If we don’t have staff competent in certain technologies, we may ask external experts to conduct interviews with candidates. In this case we make sure that the candidate's personal data is processed securely and is not further shared by the experts.

Sometimes a client wants to know which people work in the project. If this is the case, after we have shortlisted a candidate for the position we share their information with the client.

We store all candidates’ information for a 6-month period after the position is filled to be able to offer this or a similar vacancy again. Our recruitment department is located in Ukraine and Belarus, and your data is processed in both of these countries with appropriate safeguards.

With regard to the information described in this section you have the following rights:

  * the right of access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure ('right to be forgotten');
  * the right to restriction of processing;
  * the right to object; and
  * the right to lodge a complaint.

You can read what each of these rights means in the section Your rights of this Privacy Policy. Please also read Browsing the website, Using contact forms and Logs of the web server.

### Being in our Talent Directory

We may ask for your consent in order for us to have your data in our Talent Directory, so we could contact you when we have a position for you. This data includes your contact details, links to your social media profile, CV, qualifications, salary expectations, positions you have previously applied for in our company, and references.

We collect this data either from you or from your publicly accessible profiles in social media. We will take reasonable steps to inform you if we collected your personal information from a 3rd party. We don’t share this data outside our company.

We process this information for 3 years starting from the moment you gave your consent.

With regard to the information described in this section you have the following rights:

  * the right of access;
  * the right to withdraw consent;
  * the right to data portability;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure ('right to be forgotten');
  * the right to restriction of processing; and
  * the right to lodge a complaint.

You can read what each of these rights means in the section Your rights of this Privacy Policy.

### Logs of the web server

This website is located on our dedicated server which is supported by Intetics' Infrastructure Department. It collects some technical information: Client IP, Date, Requested URL, Server Response, and Response size. These data sets are used for the purposes of our legitimate interest: to troubleshoot and secure our infrastructure, to identify which articles are more in demand depending on the client’s geography, and to optimize the content of our website.

The retention period for the logs of our web server is set to 2 years.

We do not share this data with 3rd parties.

With regard to the information described in this section you have the following rights:

  * the right of access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure ('right to be forgotten');
  * the right to restriction of processing;
  * the right to object; and
  * the right to lodge a complaint.

You can read what each of these rights means in the section Your rights of this Privacy Policy.

## International transfers

This website is located in the USA, so that is where all data collection happens.

The data which is collected and/or served by 3rd party providers (Google, AddThis, Xing, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, and Microsoft) may be transferred to different countries worldwide for data processing. These data transfers are covered by the terms and privacy policies of these providers.

The data which is collected by Intetics may be transferred to our offices. We are an international company with headquarters in the USA and offices in Germany, Poland, UK, Ukraine and Belarus (details are available [here](https://intetics.com/contact)). There is no adequacy decision of the European Commission for the USA, Ukraine and Belarus, but we use standard data protection contract clauses for transfers outside the EU. The European Commission has adopted standard data protection contract clauses (known as the Model Clauses) which provide safeguards for personal information that is transferred outside of Europe. Please look at the chapter "How we protect your data" to see which measures are taken to respect your privacy.

## How we protect your data

The data which is collected on this website by 3rd party providers (Google, AddThis, Xing, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn) and the data which is stored on Microsoft are protected by them and are a subject of their terms and privacy policies. They are all industry-leading providers and have numerous certifications which confirm their ability to securely store and process sensitive data, including personal.

The data which is collected on this website by Intetics as well as the data which you entrust us under NDAs and contracts is protected by Intetics. We are an ISO/IEC 27001 certified company, follow the requirements of GDPR and take security very seriously. We maintain all necessary state-of-the-art technical and organizational measures based on the risk assessment approach to protect your data.

## Your rights

Here you can find the list of all the rights that have been referred to in the other sections of this Policy. Please read through all of them or take a look at a particular section to find out which of these rights apply to you depending on the way in which you interact with us.

As a data subject (a person whose personal data is collected, stored and processed) you have several rights under GDPR:

  *  **The right of access.** You have the right to obtain confirmation if your personal data is being processed by us. If that is the case, you can access your personal data and the following information: (a) the purposes of the processing; (b) the categories of personal data; (c) to whom the personal data has been or will be disclosed; (d) the period for which the personal data will be stored, or the criteria used to determine that period. If you would like to have a copy of your personal data from us, we will provide it if: (1) you provide us with a proof of your identity, (2) it will not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others. The first copy will be provided for free, and for any further copies we may charge a reasonable fee based on the associated administrative costs.
  *  **The right to rectification.** You have the right to demand that we correct without undue delay your personal data which we have in our systems if it is inaccurate or incomplete.
  *  **The right to erasure ('right to be forgotten').** You have the right to demand that we erase your personal data, and we shall erase it without undue delay where one of the following grounds applies: (a) the data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it is was processed; (b) you withdraw consent on which the processing is based, and where there is no other legal ground for the processing; (c) you object to the processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds; (d) your personal data has been unlawfully processed; (e) your personal data has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation.
  *  **The right to restriction of processing.** You have the right to restrict our capacity and ability to process your data where one of the following applies: (a) you contest the accuracy of your personal data and we are verifying it; (b) the processing is unlawful and you want to restrict it instead of erasure; (c) we no longer need your personal data, but you need it for some legal reasons; (d) you have objected to processing and we are verifying whether the legitimate grounds override your request.
  *  **The right to data portability.** You have the right to receive your personal data which you provided us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit that data to another company, where: (a) the processing is based on your consent or on a contract; and (b) the processing is carried out by automated means. Where technically feasible, you can demand us to transmit that data directly to another company.
  *  **The right to object.** You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data based on our legitimate interests. We shall no longer process your personal data unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing of, or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. Where personal data is processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for such marketing purposes.
  *  **Automated individual decision-making, including profiling.** You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects on you. Please note that we don’t make any automated decisions including profiling based on information that we have about you.
  *  **The right to withdraw consent.** You have the right to withdraw your consent for the processing of your personal data at any time. You can retract your consent at anytime by submitting a request to be removed from our mailing list via our [contact form](https://intetics.com/contact). The withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
  *  **The right to lodge a complaint.** You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes GDPR.
